<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>https://jalyn.co/tags/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 16:12:18 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jalyn.co/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The seven sins (and why my top-ranked is gluttony)</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/gluttony/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 16:12:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/gluttony/</guid>
      <description>Out of the seven sins, I feel like my top three rotate between gluttony, sloth and pride.
Some days, I am one with sloth; I am the sloth; sloth becomes me, etc.
Gluttony, on the other hand, strikes me in cycles.
(Note: Possible trigger for disordered eating here!)
I try to put guardrails on my life, with habits like meal prepping, or working out and hitting a specific step count every day.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Out of the seven sins, I feel like my top three rotate between gluttony, sloth and pride.</p>
<p>Some days, I am one with sloth; I am the sloth; sloth becomes me, etc.</p>
<p>Gluttony, on the other hand, strikes me in cycles.</p>
<p>(Note: Possible trigger for disordered eating here!)</p>
<p>I try to put guardrails on my life, with habits like meal prepping, or working out and hitting a specific step count every day.</p>
<p>This year… has been kind of rough, on all these aspects. I’m not sure what has changed, and if it’s just an accelerated version of burnout in the time of this pandemic, but it is somehow significantly worse than this time last year.</p>
<p>Instead of meal prepping, I either:</p>
<ul>
<li>Skip a meal because there’s nothing I really want to eat, or;</li>
<li>Go on my phone and start (to the tune of Waving Through a Window) tap-tap-tapping for food to magically show up at my door steps, anytime from 30 to 50 minutes later</li>
</ul>
<p>In Thomas Aquinas’ <a href="https://www.newadvent.org/summa/3148.htm#article4"   target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Summa Theologica</a>, he outlined the five ways that gluttony is committed. These include food that is:</p>
<ul>
<li>too expensive (I have two extremes with my cravings: 40 cents instant noodles, or a $250 buffet)</li>
<li>too elaborately prepared (Maybe not so much on this one? Score?)</li>
<li>too much in quantity ()</li>
<li>eaten too quickly (I guess? It depends. If I’m eating by myself, I tend to do it quite fast so that I can do other things)</li>
<li>eaten too early (my teammates might dispute this, because I eat lunch at 3pm, reallll healthily like, so… reverse-gluttony?)</li>
</ul>
<p>Oooh, boy. Lots to unpack here. I also know that the only way is through, so I just have to identify my obstacles in meal prepping again to do it more consistently now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy 30th, World Wide Web!</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/www/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 16:13:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/www/</guid>
      <description>Age 6 (maybe 7?) I get my first email address. My journey to start understanding this WWW thing begins properly.
Age 11 My computer/internet usage time is limited by two factors: Sharing a single desktop computer with my sister, and school/homework. Still, I find time to use it.
I research for a presentation all about dolphins, complete with videos and .wav sounds that I download from different webpages. Pretty sure it’s an awesome presentation.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="age-6-maybe-7">Age 6 (maybe 7?)</h3>
<p>I get my first email address. My journey to start understanding this WWW thing begins properly.</p>
<h3 id="age-11">Age 11</h3>
<p>My computer/internet usage time is limited by two factors: Sharing a single desktop computer with my sister, and school/homework. Still, I find time to use it.</p>
<p>I research for a presentation all about dolphins, complete with videos and .wav sounds that I download from different webpages. Pretty sure it’s an awesome presentation.</p>
<h3 id="age-12">Age 12</h3>
<p>I win third place at a website building competition.</p>
<p>My secret to the reason why I learned to code? Neopets.</p>
<h3 id="age-14">Age 14</h3>
<p>I discover so many things that are just starting to get its footing: <a href="/beginnings/"  >Blogger, LiveJournal, hosting on someone’s cool-sounding domain as a subdomain</a>; fandom forums; Yahoo Groups; Friendster, e-greetings; Napster and then later, LimeWire; Geocities…</p>
<p>I don’t know that it’ll be referred to in the future as the dot com bust, but here we are.</p>
<h3 id="age-16">Age 16</h3>
<p>I switch between appearing offline and online on MSN Messenger, hoping for specific someones to notice me and strike up a conversation.</p>
<p>In March of this year, I’ll buy jalyn.org. Unfortunately, like most good things that have happened in my life, I don’t keep a good hold of it, and it’ll be under the ownership of a domain squatter from 2006 onwards.</p>
<p>Even more unfortunately, my name is now also the name of a prescription medicine used by men to treat the symptoms of an enlarged prostate.</p>
<p>Around this time I also start earning some money on the web — installing WordPress and other web-based software for people (sometimes not even for actual money, but credits towards hosting) and providing customer service support for web hosting companies. Everything just seems to click in my head, and it’s easy.</p>
<h3 id="age-17">Age 17</h3>
<p>I’m an arrogant little shit in my web design class, and start using divs in my code with an externally-linked CSS file, ignoring the lecturer’s requirement for us to use tables for layouts and in-line styling. I don’t get a good grade in the class.</p>
<p>Oh, also, I get a BlackBerry, and completely go over my monthly 15 MB limit in about two hours flat.</p>
<h3 id="age-32-right-now">Age 32, right now.</h3>
<p>Honestly, I feel like I’ve been taking the world wide web for granted.</p>
<p>Beyond the primary function it serves in my life, it has also brought me closer to people I never would have met without the internet/web. I’ve met best friends through so many different ways on the web, done so many things — like this blog! but also other creative endeavors, and of course, some of my work — and will continue to do them.</p>
<p>Pretty amazing for 30 years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 16:55:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>I want to start a blog.
This has been something that has been on my mind for the past ten years, although if I’m being honest with myself (and that’s the goal here!), it has definitely been something I’ve thought of for way longer than the last decade.
I’ve flirted with Blogger as a teen, painstakingly linking my high school friends’ blogs in the sidebar and refreshing each of them daily, before I discovered RSS (and before it faded away).</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I want to start a blog.</p>
<p>This has been something that has been on my mind for the past ten years, although if I’m being honest with myself (and that’s the goal here!), it has definitely been something I’ve thought of for way longer than the last decade.</p>
<p>I’ve flirted with Blogger as a teen, painstakingly linking my high school friends’ blogs in the sidebar and refreshing each of them daily, before I discovered RSS (and before it faded away). I had a carefully curated LiveJournal about my favorite TV shows and films and music, and for a few years, it was such a big part of my life online.</p>
<p>I’d even installed easily a dozen or so WordPress blogs when I started freelancing as a web designer when I was 18, and created endless mental reminders for myself to get the ball rolling on one myself when the blogs I was reading shifted into the mainstream.</p>
<p>Yet, the daunting expectations of being consistent in writing and putting something out into the world, coupled with the imposter syndrome of feeling like my thoughts aren’t worthy enough of documentation gave me pause in my steps towards doing just that.</p>
<p>There isn’t really a grand plan or strategy in place for this little corner of the internet I’m parking myself in, though. Plenty of things and conversations I want to have with people, and it would probably reflect the intersections of my life, my values, and things I find interesting.</p>
<p>More likely than not, it would chronicle my journey in optimizing my life, my path to financial independence, my attempts at intentionality and minimalism, and my lifelong pursuit of fitness (both physical and mental!).</p>
<p>I want to start a blog, and so, as a new year and decade begins – here I am.</p>
<p>Hello, world!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
