<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Fitness on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/fitness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fitness on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 15:55:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/fitness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On fitness, strength, and barely knowing what to do next</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/fitness-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 15:55:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/fitness-strength/</guid>
      <description>I hurt my back in 2018.
It’s not a long story, but a pretty convoluted one: On the morning of my flight back home from London, I tripped down the stairs of our apartment and spent the commute to the airport, and the flight back home with a sprained ankle.
At that point, I’ve been consistently going to the gym for about a year — I remember doing modified bodyweight sessions during the trip too — but had to pause that with the ankle.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I hurt my back in 2018.</p>
<p>It’s not a long story, but a pretty convoluted one: On the morning of my flight back home from London, I tripped down the stairs of our apartment and spent the commute to the airport, and the flight back home with a sprained ankle.</p>
<p>At that point, I’ve been consistently going to the gym for about a year — I remember doing modified bodyweight sessions during the trip too — but had to pause that with the ankle.</p>
<p>The first session back after a couple of months, I was really pumped to be back. It was my usual routine: Get to the gym at my workplace, do a few sets of squats, deadlifts, lat pulldowns and a few other movements.</p>
<p>Too pumped, maybe. I was super careful not to roll and hurt my ankle again.</p>
<p>Instead, I did <em>something</em> to my back. I don’t know what it was exactly, but I just remember tweaking it during the session, thinking it was nothing, then progressively getting more scared of how painful it was while I was on the way home.</p>
<p>That’s the thing about memories — I remember what I was wearing (blue exercise top, shorts, my Timberland boots because I switch out my gym shoes in the office), and I remember the route to the train station and desperately trying to block out the pain, as the adrenaline of the session faded away.</p>
<p>I bend down, ostensibly pretending to tie my shoelaces to any onlookers. I don&rsquo;t know what that was important.</p>
<p>What happened next is that for the last three and a half years, I’ve been letting that injury cloud my mind.</p>
<hr>
<p>I went to test for my resting metabolic rate yesterday. As I’ve suspected, my resting metabolic rate is 30% less than the average person my size. I know this because I’ve been eating like an asshole, knowing that my muscles are wasting away anyway.</p>
<p>Casey Johnston, aka Ask A Swole Woman, has <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CL-CJzvJxG2/?utm_source=ig_web_copy_link"   target="_blank" rel="noopener" >a great post illustrating what’s been happening to my body</a>.</p>
<p>I’m at the ‘<em>muscle has gone bye bye</em>’ stage</p>
<hr>
<p>I’m at a bit of a standstill, I think. What I can do to fix it is to get back to building muscles again, and for that to happen, first I need to get back to seeing a physio — hopefully one who wouldn’t just laugh at my terrible form when doing the bird dog exercise.</p>
<p>But actually, first I need a referral be able to make a claim from the insurance.</p>
<p>Which means that first, I need to go to my GP.</p>
<p><em>Actually</em>, first, I need to go to <em>a</em> GP that is on the insurer’s list.</p>
<p>Kidding aside, there’s just a lot of steps and hoops to go through, and I’m not particularly enthused about that.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
