<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Stoicism on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>https://jalyn.co/tags/stoicism/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stoicism on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 15:59:46 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jalyn.co/tags/stoicism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>In/out of control</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 15:59:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/control/</guid>
      <description>My mentor asked me a simple question when I was catching up with her: What’s in your control, and what’s not?
—
I’ve touched on this topic before, while talking about stoicism and what we can control. That was February of this year, which seems both like a short time and a lifetime ago. I had a pretty pithy line to summarize then:
Things happen, and the only thing we can control is how we respond to them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My mentor asked me a simple question when I was catching up with her: What’s in your control, and what’s not?</p>
<p>—</p>
<p>I’ve touched on this topic before, while talking about <a href="/control"  >stoicism and what we can control</a>. That was February of this year, which seems both like a short time and a lifetime ago. I had a pretty pithy line to summarize then:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Things happen, and the only thing we can control is how we respond to them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Well, turns out, in life, things do happen.</p>
<p>With work, what is it that I can control? What is it that I struggle with accepting that I can’t control?</p>
<h3 id="i-cant-control">I can’t control:</h3>
<ul>
<li>The (types of) clients the team engages with</li>
<li>Other people’s actions, reactions, and decisions</li>
<li>Whether people would participate in one thing, and not another</li>
<li>How others perceive me</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="what-i-can">What I can:</h3>
<ul>
<li>How I react to these things happening</li>
<li>How I respond — a slight nuanced difference from the first thing, which is more in the moment</li>
<li>How much action I take, or do not take</li>
<li>The mindfulness I take towards my actions</li>
</ul>
<p>I vaguely alluded to a big shocking announcement at work last week; cue me googling ‘what to do when manager is laid off’ — <a href="/work-ethics"  >the same manager that was understanding of my morals at work</a> — and still trying to process it, about a week and a half after.</p>
<p>I’m still trying to figure out what it means for me (my own job security, my next step forward, building my promotion case) but it’s definitely given me a lot to think about, when I’m not being busy with actual work and calls, and dealing with bad timing (on my part) to try and get a CSR initiative off the ground.</p>
<p>I’m still on that adjusted working week — from Sunday to Thursday — for at least two more weeks, and I don’t think I’m ever going to get used to that, as long as the rest of my team is on Monday to Friday.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stoicism, and what we can control</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/stoic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 16:27:43 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/stoic/</guid>
      <description>I am the one thing in life I can control, Hamilton‘s Aaron Burr sings.
I grew up in a household where behaviours are mostly reactive, when sometimes it felt like things happening to you are a personal affront. It’s something that I have grown to reject, as I grew older (and hopefully wiser), but I also wanted a way to frame my thoughts and attitudes around things.
That’s when I discovered stoicism.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am the one thing in life I can control, <em>Hamilton</em>‘s Aaron Burr sings.</p>
<p>I grew up in a household where behaviours are mostly reactive, when sometimes it felt like things happening to you are a personal affront. It’s something that I have grown to reject, as I grew older (and hopefully wiser), but I also wanted a way to frame my thoughts and attitudes around things.</p>
<p>That’s when I discovered stoicism.</p>
<p>There’s a lot with stoicism that leaves me scratching my head, confused if these men (all of them are, naturally) really did live their lives void of emotion when bad things happen, and worshipped logical thought as its own god.</p>
<p>Epicetetus wrote, “If, for example, you are fond of a specific ceramic cup, remind yourself that it is only ceramic cups in general of which you are fond. Then, if it breaks, you will not be disturbed.”</p>
<p>I thought, yeah, that makes sense. Things belong to you, and you don’t belong to things.</p>
<p>Then, he followed it up with, “If you kiss your child, or your wife, say that you only kiss things which are human, and thus you will not be disturbed if either of them dies.”</p>
<hr>
<p>Excuse me, <em>what</em>?</p>
<hr>
<p>I dove into Marcus Aurelius’ Meditations too.</p>
<p>That was an interesting read – I know it’s heralded as one of the leading texts to stoicism, and the emperor himself is regarded as one of the most influential humans and not just on stoicism. Some parts of the journal definitely felt like he was trying to convince himself that stoicism is the answer, too. It made sense, since he’d apparently never intended these private journal entries to be published.</p>
<p>I know if my journal entries, safely logged on Day One, were to be published one day, people would be befuddled too.</p>
<p>Ultimately, stoicism is still a domain that I’m <em>really</em> new at and exploring the different facets of.</p>
<p>At a glance, it seems like an answer, though at this point I’m not quite sure what the exact question is.</p>
<p>I’m still the one thing in life that I can control, which means: Things happen, and the only thing we can control is how we respond to them.</p>
<p>So I’m going to take this, probably struggle with it for a long time, but hey. At least I’ll be trying.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
