<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>https://jalyn.co/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 19:24:50 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jalyn.co/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On Photo Storage &amp; Google&#39;s Take-Backsies</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/photo-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 19:24:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/photo-storage/</guid>
      <description>“Noooooo,” I typed dramatically to my chats after taking a screenshot of this storage change from Google. To recap: From June 2021, high quality photos uploaded to Google Photos will count towards the storage limit, instead of the current unlimited uploading.
I’ve talked a little before my digital clutter in general, and glossed over how my cloud storage is set up. I’ve had Dropbox for years before I let it lapse this year, and was planning on getting a Google One subscription.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>“Noooooo,” I typed dramatically to my chats after taking a screenshot of this <a href="https://blog.google/products/photos/storage-changes/"   target="_blank" rel="noopener" >storage change from Google</a>. To recap: From June 2021, high quality photos uploaded to Google Photos will count towards the storage limit, instead of the current unlimited uploading.</p>
<p>I’ve talked a little before <a href="https://jalyn.co/digital-hoarding/"   target="_blank" rel="noopener" >my digital clutter</a> in general, and glossed over how my cloud storage is set up. I’ve had Dropbox for years before I let it lapse this year, and was planning on getting a Google One subscription. That is, until I realized that photo storage was going to be a non-issue with Google Photos, and held off getting a plan.</p>
<p>Until now.</p>
<p>Honestly, that pause for effect is a little unwarranted — it’s $28/year for me, and a manageable amount for the value it would bring.</p>
<p>Of my digital assets, photos and videos storage remain the thing that is the most cluttered for me. I don’t take the time to go through each photo and only keep things that matter. Screenshots make up a not-insignificant percentage of my images.</p>
<p>Occupational hazard, you might say.</p>
<p>So, I guess this is as good a time to carve a new intentional practice with my images:</p>
<ul>
<li>Review the photos and videos on my phone and delete bad and irrelevant files on an ongoing basis</li>
<li>Create automated workflows to shift other files where they need to be:
<ul>
<li>Store design-related screenshots on a Figma board</li>
<li>Upload important images and screenshots on Notion</li>
<li>Back up important images and videos via the Google Photos app</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Now, off I go to delete some photos.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
