<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>https://jalyn.co/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 16:19:26 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jalyn.co/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The commoditization of the design case study</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/design-commoditization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jun 2021 16:19:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/design-commoditization/</guid>
      <description>I’ve done, I think, four portfolio reviews with the folks over at General Assembly.
I enjoy it, mostly (sometimes the imposter syndrome kicks in and I get self-conscious about whether or not I’m bringing value to these young designers). I get to talk to groups of 3 to 6 designers from each graduating batch, and have them play back their portfolios to me.
It’s not a failing of the individuals, to be sure, but—</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve done, I think, four portfolio reviews with the folks over at General Assembly.</p>
<p>I enjoy it, mostly (sometimes the imposter syndrome kicks in and I get self-conscious about whether or not I’m bringing value to these young designers). I get to talk to groups of 3 to 6 designers from each graduating batch, and have them play back their portfolios to me.</p>
<p>It’s not a failing of the individuals, to be sure, but—</p>
<p>It. is. all. the. same.</p>
<ul>
<li>Each case study starts and ends in exactly identical ways — though some students do expand on the more insightful things rather than the process;</li>
<li>Too much emphasis on the output rather than the outcomes, even for the self-identified UX researchers of the bunch;</li>
<li>The design process used might be ‘textbook’, but things in real working situations might not play out exactly that way in those steps;</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="so-what-does-this-have-to-do-with-me">So… what does this have to do with me?</h2>
<p>I published my own portfolio in 2016 (or maybe 2017), which is a lifetime — and two jobs — ago. At that time, the UX portfolio scene hasn’t been commoditized to the same regurgitation of “the design process”. I remember scrambling to find other portfolios with case studies that I could benchmark as a best practice. You know, like a real UX nerd.</p>
<p>Looking at my own portfolio now, though, I honestly can’t tell if I would pick myself from a stack of other portfolios. It’s not the exact same design process as the GA grads have, but the construct of it is largely similar: problem statements, what we did to unpacking them, and how we came up with solutions. Pretty flows and sketches and wireframes, and then the grand reveal.</p>
<p>Anyway.</p>
<p>I do remember getting commends from reviewers during that first job search with this portfolio, on the effort made and time spent on crafting it out.</p>
<p>How do I tell this story of working on awesome stuff with awesome people, without going through this template of a case study? Much to think about, now that I’m moving along in my career.</p>
<p>I suppose that is a design problem to be solved.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
