<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>https://jalyn.co/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 20:29:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jalyn.co/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Timezone shifting</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/timezones/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 20:29:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/timezones/</guid>
      <description>Look at me, a whole month ago, breaking down and analyzing my “new” routine at work, without realizing that all of that was going to get slightly upended when I got staffed on a project based out of the UK.
Needless to say, I did not do very well with the whole work-life balance or integration part of things. Working with the team that is 7 hours behind me meant that theoretically, I should be starting my day way later, but I was consistently pulling 14+ hours during the past month, and readers… It was no fun.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Look at me, a whole month ago, breaking down and analyzing my “new” routine at work, without realizing that all of that was going to get slightly upended when I got staffed on a project based out of the UK.</p>
<p>Needless to say, I did not do very well with the whole work-life balance <em>or</em> integration part of things. Working with the team that is 7 hours behind me meant that theoretically, I should be starting my day way later, but I was consistently pulling 14+ hours during the past month, and readers… It was no fun.</p>
<p>Sometimes I feel like a fraud when I find myself reminding other people on my team to take breaks, push back, and say no to things. I know I haven’t yet mastered (or even grasped, honestly) that yet for myself, and it’s definitely something I have to work on.</p>
<p>Anyway, now that the hell month is over, I should re-prioritize my life again. I know that writing this weekly makes me happy, but I’m also (constantly) fretting about what the Purpose™ and value of this all is.</p>
<p>I want to talk about productivity and habits and personal finance and minimalism and, and, <em>and</em>, but it is a field that is super saturated — though I do have my own personal spin on things, but fundamentals remain that. I want to be better at focusing on the craft of writing, and on long-form essays, and that is a muscle that I’m not always using. I want to start thinking about writing original fiction again, and doing that. I want to dabble in creating for other mediums (podcast? video? social media?), and becoming more of an expert in those things.</p>
<p>Lots of wants in my life, and not so much time or energy to be doing those!</p>
<p>(P.S. On Sunday I fell flat on my face, nearly, and hurt my elbow trying to do an ab wheel exercise that my physio is making me do, so that’s a nice little bow to the end of the work week.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming less of a work bot</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/work-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 20:13:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/work-bot/</guid>
      <description>If you looked up the definition of sheepish, you’ll probably find my face right there. Mostly due to the fact that I have been neglecting this journaling habit, which was something I held quite proudly of for last year.
2021: never missing a week!
2022: does ‘a week’ mean anything, actually? what is this archaic concept of time we hold ourselves to? why have we shackled ourselves—-
Etc, etc.
This entire second half of the year has been a test that I have been consistently failing, I think.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you looked up the definition of <em>sheepish</em>, you’ll probably find my face right there. Mostly due to the fact that I have been neglecting this journaling habit, which was something I held quite proudly of for last year.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>2021: never missing a week!</p>
<p>2022: does ‘a week’ mean anything, actually? what is this archaic concept of time we hold ourselves to? why have we shackled ourselves—-</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Etc, etc.</p>
<hr>
<p>This entire second half of the year has been a test that I have been consistently failing, I think.</p>
<p>I find myself buried with work, and burying myself with more of it.</p>
<p>My free thoughts are fleeting, consumed by <em>the things for work I’m wasting time not doing right now</em> and <em>the things I should be doing, but I don’t have the mind space to sit down for them right now</em>. It’s pretty dire, and in no way strategic.</p>
<p>Or any good for my mental health, that I know for sure.</p>
<hr>
<p>I talk about putting guard rails a lot, but I also kick them down on my own volition. There are things I know:</p>
<p>Better at saying no.</p>
<p>Better at managing my expectations.</p>
<p>Better at putting myself first.</p>
<p>Better, for my own body and mind.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
