<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Hardware on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>https://jalyn.co/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hardware on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:54:50 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jalyn.co/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adding an iPad to my personal workflow</title>
      <link>https://jalyn.co/ipad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 09:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jalyn.co/ipad/</guid>
      <description>I’ve recently acquired an old, barely-responsive iPad in my arsenal.
It’s a 5th generation unit, and something my mother has used for at least 18 hours every day, since 2017.
Truth be told, I’m surprised that it isn’t in a worse condition, as it was used for intensive video playing for 18 hours, every single day:
There is noticeable burn in the screen, right in the middle The backlight is yellow and flickering The response time isn’t what you’ll call speedy The battery is at 70% of its capacity Those are my observations from a week’s usage, and it’s far from its hey day.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I’ve recently acquired an old, barely-responsive iPad in my arsenal.</p>
<p>It’s a 5th generation unit, and something my mother has used for at least 18 hours every day, since 2017.</p>
<p>Truth be told, I’m surprised that it isn’t in a worse condition, as it was used for intensive video playing for 18 hours, every single day:</p>
<ul>
<li>There is noticeable burn in the screen, right in the middle</li>
<li>The backlight is yellow and flickering</li>
<li>The response time isn’t what you’ll call speedy</li>
<li>The battery is at 70% of its capacity</li>
</ul>
<p>Those are my observations from a week’s usage, and it’s far from its hey day.</p>
<p>But it <em>works,</em> and I’m having fun, experimenting how it fits in my workflow.</p>
<h2 id="as-a-consumption-device">As a consumption device</h2>
<p>This is undoubtedly the lowest-hanging use case, and the one with the least friction.</p>
<p>Cutting down screen time on my phone has been a recent focus, with culprits like Reddit monopolizing much of my time and attention. Even with the app deleted on the phone!</p>
<p>I offloaded the streaming apps from my phone, and while I’ll continue to use my Kindle for reading, it looks like I can read PDF books easier on the bigger, zoomable screen.</p>
<h2 id="as-a-capture-device">As a capture device</h2>
<p>My general knowledge management system revolves around… a pen, and an internet connection. It’s something I am actively experimenting with, outside the iPad conundrum.</p>
<p><em>But</em>, until I figure that out, Notion remains my primary tool for long-form capture, and Telegram’s ability to send short messages to myself for quick capture notes.</p>
<p>Which brings me back to connectivity as a main driver of my capture system: this iPad is WiFi-only.</p>
<p>If I’m at home, it wouldn’t be the first thing I reach for when it comes to notes, and if I’m outside, it is less of a hassle to capture it on my phone, than if I were to tether a connection from it to the bigger device.</p>
<p>So, that’s a no-go for my typical note-taking.</p>
<p>But there is an edge here: scribblings and drawings.</p>
<p>Right now, I use a random notebook from Muji capturing ideas and diagrams. I haven’t figured out the offline-to-online syncing of these ideas, other than sinking in a lot of money for a reMarkable for that purpose.</p>
<p>But, I’ll be spending more time seeing if this new addition to the flow works.</p>
<h2 id="as-a-writing-device">As a writing device</h2>
<p>I was pretty delighted to realize that my keyboard connects to the iPad, even if it takes about a second for the lag to catch up.</p>
<p>Half of this article was typed half the iPad, while I’m hanging out at a cafe.</p>
<p>I’ll admit, the first question I posed to myself was: when will it ever be more convenient to go out with a keyboard and an iPad, versus going out with my (also new) MacBook Air?</p>
<p>It could be the novelty speaking, but writing on the iPad might give me an edge of focus.</p>
<p>Again, something I’ll have to experiment with a little more.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
