<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 16:11:11 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Time</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tracking-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Aug 2021 16:11:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tracking-time/</guid>
      <description>It’s 2015, and my workplace was exploring different tools for resource management.
It started when the team lead wanted a way to “sell” our services as an in-house team (and I’ll be honest, I’m not sure that quantifying time spent was the way to do it but that’s a story for another day), so we went through a few, finding the pros and cons of each before settling on Harvest.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It’s 2015, and my workplace was exploring different tools for resource management.</p>
<p>It started when the team lead wanted a way to “sell” our services as an in-house team (and I’ll be honest, I’m not sure that quantifying time spent was the way to do it but that’s a story for another day), so we went through a few, finding the pros and cons of each before settling on Harvest.</p>
<p>I think it’s because it was the cheapest per seat, maybe?</p>
<p>But that whole exercise of finding a tool and figuring out what worked and what didn’t also led me to think about my <em>own</em> hours, outside of work.</p>
<p>I hadn’t come across <a href="https://lauravanderkam.com/2017/09/welcome-168-hours-time-tracking-challenge/"   target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Laura Vanderkam</a>‘s content at that point, so it was trial and error on my part to figuring out what I was tracking.</p>
<p>I remember polling my friends and colleagues about my information architecture — or really just categories or buckets of time, occupational hazard aside — and trying to see if I was being too pedantic about some things, and too general for others.</p>
<p>So… I guess the question begs: Why do I track my time?</p>
<p>It started out as a way for me to find out where I was spending (wasting) my time — back in 2015, the time I took to commute was definitely an issue on my mind, and I feel like being able to clock that time made me aware of 1) how much it was, and 2) where it ranked amongst my other ‘smaller’ activities, like going to the gym.</p>
<p>More than that, I figured that if I knew what I was doing, and for how long, I could in theory optimize my time and productivity. I also remember thinking a lot about what that tipping point would be, for me to use money to buy time, instead of spending my time to get money instead.</p>
<h3 id="things-i-should-know-with-common-sense-but-instead-knew-for-sure">Things I should know with common sense, but instead knew for sure:</h3>
<ul>
<li>I spend way too much time beyond my 40 hours a week for work</li>
<li>(That isn’t counting the work-adjacent activity, which includes things like training, development courses/classes that are specifically applied at work, and as of 2021, mentoring sessions)</li>
<li>Meal prep is a really effective time saver, even though the upfront cost of it seems high (I spend about 45 minutes every Sunday doing it, compared to ~25 minutes a day)</li>
<li>Being lazy in bed is an actual bad habit of mine</li>
<li>Sometimes I chunk a lot of activity under “Internet”, even though I have specific buckets for media consumption, reading, fandom stuff etc. Pretty sure that’s indicative of a bigger problem, which is that I (falsely) think I can multitask</li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>That said, Toggl — the app I’ve been using since 2015 — <a href="https://twitter.com/toggltrack/status/1431554352506884096"   target="_blank" rel="noopener" >had a functional error</a> over the weekend, and it’s thrown me off the loop as I keep trying to open the app on my phone. Hopefully that gets resolved soon.</p>
<p>Let me know if you try out tracking your time, even if just for a week, and if you see any surprises in there!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A snapshot of my waking moments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/waking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 16:23:41 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/waking/</guid>
      <description>When I wake up, I reach for my phone.
Not checking for messages or notifications (though sometimes I sneak a glimpse), but to start a new entry in my daily log on Notion.
The first thing I do is start typing all that I remember from — hopefully — a night of dreaming. I dream quite vividly, and it’s a race against time to record that down, translating something that had made so much sense in dream land to something that is coherent in actual words.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When I wake up, I reach for my phone.</p>
<p>Not checking for messages or notifications (though sometimes I sneak a glimpse), but to start a new entry in my daily log on Notion.</p>
<p>The first thing I do is start typing all that I remember from — hopefully — a night of dreaming. I dream quite vividly, and it’s a race against time to record that down, translating something that had made so much sense in dream land to something that is coherent in actual words.</p>
<p>(Yesterday I dreamt I’d forgotten my mask and had to use the hood from my hoodie to cover my face while walking.</p>
<p>The day before: I had to hide in the toilets from a man who was hunting me but it wasn’t not working, and he was also the father of the witches who’s at fault for all the deaths (???).</p>
<p>Yeah. Exciting!)</p>
<p>When I’m done with scrambling to write everything I can remember before they all dissolve into wisps of nothingness in my memory, I fill up the title of the entry with one thing I’m grateful for in my life.</p>
<p>These days, I find that I’m thankful for these general patterns:</p>
<ul>
<li>Getting through a work day or week</li>
<li>Having free time/anticipating free time</li>
<li>Spending quality time with people</li>
</ul>
<p>Thematically, they all have to do with time and how I spend it, which tracks.</p>
<p>(And then I proceed to spend another twenty minutes in bed just lazing.)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
