<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mindset on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mindset/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mindset on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 20:28:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reframe, rethink</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reframe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 20:28:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reframe/</guid>
      <description>(Inspired by Brianna Wiest’s 101 Essays That Will Change The Way You Think)
You’re still functional — physically, at least. You can walk and you can sit, and you can shrug off the pain when it gets a little too much. You hold on to your values, even when it’s easier to just go with the path of least resistance. You can be proud of who you are. Work is tough, and some days it’s annoying, but so many people would love to be doing what you do.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(Inspired by Brianna Wiest’s 101 Essays That Will Change The Way You Think)</p>
<ol>
<li>You’re still functional — physically, at least. You can walk and you can sit, and you can shrug off the pain when it gets a little too much.</li>
<li>You hold on to your values, even when it’s easier to just go with the path of least resistance. You can be proud of who you are.</li>
<li>Work is tough, and some days it’s annoying, but so many people would love to be doing what you do.</li>
<li>You earn enough to live comfortably, to go where you want and eat what you desire; enough to live on your own terms.</li>
<li>You’re allowed to think and ponder about what <em>living on your own terms</em> mean, and know that even though life isn’t ideal or where you’d thought it would be, it’s still a journey to get to where you envision it to be.</li>
<li>You have the weekend to decompress, even if decompressing means losing track of time as you doom-scroll through Reddit.</li>
<li>You just spent a good hour preparing for your lunches in the week ahead, and that is going to help with keeping track of actually eating lunch, which is something that has been a miss for so much of the last two years.</li>
<li>You have comfort shows and movies that you can dive back into; an embrace into a familiarity that makes your brain feel happy.</li>
<li>You have amazing friends. Quality &gt; quantity, especially in this case.</li>
<li>You think about all the different ways to get better, and to be better. You might fail and stumble along the way, but you’re still trying. You’re figuring it out. You’re still here.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#IAmRemarkable</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/iamremarkable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 14:49:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/iamremarkable/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago, I had the pleasure of attending an #IAmRemarkable session hosted by Akua Nyame-Mensah. The hour and a half flew past like it was nothing, and filled me with the hope that one day, too, I will not be filled with dread when it comes to talking about my own achievements.
(Even typing that! “My own achievements”…)
Why I attended this More than just for personal growth though, I definitely want the ladies and other marginalized members of my team to be able to have the confidence and competence to talk about what they have done and achieved.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Two weeks ago, I had the pleasure of attending an <a href="https://iamremarkable.withgoogle.com/"   target="_blank" rel="noopener" >#IAmRemarkable</a> session hosted by <a href="https://www.akuanm.com/"   target="_blank" rel="noopener" >Akua Nyame-Mensah</a>. The hour and a half flew past like it was nothing, and filled me with the hope that one day, too, I will not be filled with dread when it comes to talking about my own achievements.</p>
<p>(Even typing that! “My own achievements”…)</p>
<h2 id="why-i-attended-this">Why I attended this</h2>
<p>More than just for personal growth though, I definitely want the ladies and other marginalized members of my team to be able to have the confidence and competence to talk about what they have done and achieved.</p>
<p>I’ve never been someone who likes talking about myself, and I used to prefer sticking to the background and “doing the work” — just like a good little worker should, I thought. It served me well for a few years early in my career, because I had bosses who noticed the good work done, and I was rewarded appropriately.</p>
<p>When I moved to a consultancy, that changed. It was a culture shock in that area, being given the agency to chart your own career and having that be the norm. It wasn’t the greatest of workplaces though, and there were a lot of factors going into an appraisal beyond “work” done, like utilization hours… and how well you knew your leaders.</p>
<p>Now, though, where I work? There has been a giant shift to ‘owning’ your career, and the biggest change is having to put your own promotion package together and deciding when you’re ready to take the leap, instead of passively waiting for your manager to tell you that you’re ready. I went through that whole process earlier this year, and it was nerve-wracking and filled me up with so much imposter syndrome.</p>
<h2 id="moving-from-criticizing-to-self-love">Moving from criticizing to self-love</h2>
<p>There was definitely a lot of emphasis on shifting our mindsets, and moving yourself from one end of this spectrum to the other:</p>
<p>Criticizing → Constructive criticism → Self promotion → Self-love</p>
<h2 id="iamremarkable-because">#IAmRemarkable, because:</h2>
<p>The workshop also included some time for us to think about our own #IAmRemarkable statements, both writing them down and speaking out loud (or typing it in the chat).</p>
<p>I’m not gonna lie, I had to google for some inspiration because I needed a starting point, but here are my statements just in case I come up in your search, and you needed something to guide you too</p>
<ul>
<li>#IAmRemarkable, because I am always looking out for my team’s well-being</li>
<li>#IAmRemarkable, because I always want to do better and <em>be</em> better</li>
<li>#IAmRemarkable, because I am resilient through life changes and revelations</li>
<li>#IAmRemarkable, because I pay attention to the small details</li>
<li>#IAmRemarkable, because I try to live through my <a href="/authentic-life"  >core values</a> and using them to guide my decisions</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
