<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Mindset on Jalyn Cai</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/mindset/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mindset on Jalyn Cai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 20:28:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reframe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/reframe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 20:28:59 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/reframe/</guid>
      <description>(Inspired by Brianna Wiest’s 101 Essays That Will Change The Way You Think)
You’re still functional — physically, at least. You can walk and you can sit, and you can shrug off the pain when it gets a little too much. You hold on to your values, even when it’s easier to just go with the path of least resistance. You can be proud of who you are. Work is tough, and some days it’s annoying, but so many people would love to be doing what you do.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(Inspired by Brianna Wiest’s 101 Essays That Will Change The Way You Think)</p>
<ol>
<li>You’re still functional — physically, at least. You can walk and you can sit, and you can shrug off the pain when it gets a little too much.</li>
<li>You hold on to your values, even when it’s easier to just go with the path of least resistance. You can be proud of who you are.</li>
<li>Work is tough, and some days it’s annoying, but so many people would love to be doing what you do.</li>
<li>You earn enough to live comfortably, to go where you want and eat what you desire; enough to live on your own terms.</li>
<li>You’re allowed to think and ponder about what <em>living on your own terms</em> mean, and know that even though life isn’t ideal or where you’d thought it would be, it’s still a journey to get to where you envision it to be.</li>
<li>You have the weekend to decompress, even if decompressing means losing track of time as you doom-scroll through Reddit.</li>
<li>You just spent a good hour preparing for your lunches in the week ahead, and that is going to help with keeping track of actually eating lunch, which is something that has been a miss for so much of the last two years.</li>
<li>You have comfort shows and movies that you can dive back into; an embrace into a familiarity that makes your brain feel happy.</li>
<li>You have amazing friends. Quality &gt; quantity, especially in this case.</li>
<li>You think about all the different ways to get better, and to be better. You might fail and stumble along the way, but you’re still trying. You’re figuring it out. You’re still here.</li>
</ol>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
